

## EVANGELINE EMANUEL

### **Professional Summary**

Detail-oriented Geospatial Imagery Specialist with educational background and technical expertise working in Remote Sensing and GIS. Knowledgeable about compiling, organizing and reporting on data for diverse applications. Thorough and systematic with outstanding verbal and written communication abilities. Worked with multiple agencies to gather imagery and data for research, investigation and analysis. Reliable in completing accurate work according to specifications.

### Work History

### Teleperformance Canada - Technical Support Advisor

Toronto, ON

09/2021 - Current

- Accurately identified customer inquiries by building excellent rapport & confidence, analyzing their needs, and taking strategic action in a timely manner
- Provide excellent customer support through active listening on every interaction while adjusting support approach to accommodate all levels of customer experience
- Troubleshoot mobile technology, equipment and system problems while educating the customer on support options and steps being taken to resolve the issue
- Served as primary point of contact for triaging technical issues.

# National Remote Sensing Centre, Indian Space Research Organization - GIS Apprentice

Hyderabad, India

01/2019 - 04/2019

- GIS Apprentice within National Remote Sensing Centre, Indian Space Research Organization, which is responsible for remote sensing satellite data acquisition and processing, aerial remote sensing and decision support for disaster management.
- Combined Sentinel-1, Sentinel-2 and ground data to generate area specific geographic maps.
- Analyzed the temporal backscatter signature as well as NDVI values of soybean and other competing crops (rice, cotton) grown in Hyderabad using SNAP, ERDAS Imagine and ArcGIS software.
- Worked alongside with other scientists on this project, which led to a series of changes from initial plan to final output of a series of maps depicting the change in crop mapping trends.

■ evangelineemanuel07@gmail.com

437 973 0114

• Hamilton, ON L8K1W3

#### Links

• <u>linkedin.com/in/evangeline-emanuel-</u> 154120126

#### Skills

#### **SOFTWARE**

- Adobe Illustrator 2022
- Autodesk: Civil 3D 2021 Metric, Infraworks
- ESRI Suite: ArcGIS Pro 2.9.1, ArcGIS Online
- Google Maps
- Microsoft: SQL Server, Office 365
- PCI Geomatica
- Visual Studio

#### **LANGUAGES**

- CSS
- HTML
- Python
- R
- C#
- SQL

#### Anand Agricultural University - GIS Apprentice

Anand, Gujarat, India

07/2018 - 12/2018

- Responsible for detecting and monitoring Vegetation Indices studies to predict the change in respective indices' pattern in respect to rainfall and soil moisture using satellite data
- Combined MODIS (for measuring NDVI (Normalized Difference Vegetation Index) and EVI (Enhanced Vegetation Index)) and AMSR-E (for measuring soil moisture) data to generate unified geographic mapping information.
- Created charts and other maps based on project-specific requirements in ENVI, Excel and MATLAB

#### Anand Agricultural University - GIS Apprentice

Anand, Gujarat, India

01/2018 - 05/2018

- Gujarat (area of interest) being in semi-arid region has less rainfall and lack of irrigation facility also utilizes groundwater for farming practices.
  This decline in groundwater enforced policy makers to find alternative source for irrigation in form of canal through Narmada River in Gujarat.
- This study highlights change in soil moisture and its dependency on rainfall after the implementation of canal in 2008.
- Using Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer Earth Observing System Multi-year soil moisture data for the period of monsoon June to September were analyzed for the years 2002 to 2017. A shift in the early soil wetness pattern has been observed during 2002 to 2017 in most of the study region.

#### **Anand Agricultural University - Statistics Apprentice**

Anand, Gujarat, India

01/2017 - 05/2017

- Randomized Block Design is one of the most widely used experimental design in agricultural research.
- Developed a web application for combined analysis of variance using Randomized Block Design for a given plot using HTML, Javascript and CSS.
- Mentored peer students through college hours and one-on-one communication.
- Advanced knowledge of field continuously through personal coursework and additional study to best help professor and fellow students.

#### **Education**

# Fanshawe College of Applied Arts and Technology

London, ON 06/2021

Post Graduate Certificate: GIS Applications Specialist

# Fanshawe College of Applied Arts and Technology

London, ON 09/2020 Post Graduate Certificate: Agribusiness

Management

#### **Anand Agricultural University**

Gujarat, India 01/2020 Bachelor of Technology: Agricultural Information Technology